nvu.com 2006-10-18

# Linspire.com - Privacy Policy

|    
  
Effective Date of Current Policy: February 15, 2005    
Linspire Privacy Policy    
Linspire, Inc. ("Linspire," "we," "us") shares your concerns about the protection of your personal information online. This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes our practices regarding the collection and use of information through our website, located at www.linspire.com, any of our micro sites and any web pages viewable through our CNR software application (collectively, the "Site"). By using the Site or obtaining any product or service through this Site, you agree to the collection and use of information as set forth in this Policy. If you do not agree to this Policy, please do not use the Site.

We may from time to time update this Policy. We will notify you of changes to the Policy by posting the updated Policy on this page. We ask that you bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure continuing familiarity with the most current version of the Policy. You can determine when this Policy was last revised bychecking the "Effective Date of Current Policy" legend at the top of the Policy. 

**What Information We Collect**  
Linspire collects two types of information during your visits to our Site. 

First, we collect non-personally identifiable information. When visitors come to our Site, we collect and aggregate information indicating, among other things, which pages of the Site were visited, the order in which they were visited and which links were "clicked." Collecting such information involves logging the IP addresses, operating system and browser software used by each visitor to the Site. Although such information is not personally identifiable, it may be possible to determine from an IP address a visitor's Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of the visitor's point of connectivity. 

We also use "cookies" and other tracking technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information regarding you. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser. Cookies make it possible for us to recognize your browser when you visit our Site. By doing this, we can personalize your return visits and save you time during login and checkout. Your browser must be set to accept cookies in order for you to enjoy the benefits of being a registered user of the Site. 

Second, we collect personal and personally identifiable information such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, credit card number and information concerning software downloaded, products and content purchased, accessed and/or downloaded through our products and services. 

**How We Use Collected Information**  
Please take some time to familiarize yourself with the different ways that Linspire uses the information that we gather. Keep in mind that, while we encourage all third parties involved in running our business to adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our visitors and to otherwise handle personally identifiable information in a responsible manner, we cannot and do not assume any responsibility for any actions or omissions of third parties, including the manner in which they use information received either from Linspire or independently. 

**_Non-personally identifiable information_**  
Linspire uses non-personally identifiable information, such as your IP address and the pages that you visit on our Site, to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer our Site and improve Site-related services and features. Your IP address and other non-personally identifiable information also may be used to gather broad demographic information and to recognize customer traffic patterns and Site usage trends. This information aids us in merchandising and in developing the design and layout of the Site.

Linspire may also collect diagnostic information and hardware specifications in order to provide you with support and troubleshooting services. 

In addition, the very first time a Linspire computer starts up, our CNR software application checks in with our server to look for updates and security patches. At that time, we record information such as the IP address and product specification information, including the version numbers of our operating system and CNR software application, the language type, and a builder ID number (which identifies the builder that provided you with the software). Also at this time, CNR assigns a random number to your computer. All of this information is recorded for purposes of paying royalties and licenses to third party providers, for marketing purposes, and for enforcing our policies and procedures.

We also may share aggregated statistical data and other non-personally identifiable information with our current and potential business partners, and with our service providers. 

**_Personally identifiable information_**  
Linspire uses personally identifiable information collected from you to: 

  * complete transactions initiated by you (such as the sale and delivery of products and services)
  * provide support services
  * get in touch with you when necessary
  * contact you to make sure you are satisfied with our goods and services or to find out how we can serve you better
  * conduct in-depth marketing research regarding our customers and potential customers
  * verify access to access-restricted services such as our CNR Service, Forums and your "My.Linspire" account
  * track content accesses and downloads for purposes of paying royalties and licenses to third party providers, for marketing purposes, and for enforcing our policies and procedures
  * offer you product upgrades; and auto-update downloaded products.

Financial informatiion (credit card numbers, credit card expiration dates, billing address, and so forth) is used to bill you for products and services. You may, from time to time, receive information from us regarding new features, new products and services and special offers we think you'll find valuable. If you'd like to opt out of receiving future mailings from Linspire, please follow the procedure outlined in the Choice/Opt-out section below.

Linspire also may use your personally identifiable information to "pre-populate" forms that are used by the Site to facilitate transactions with us. Other types of use by us of personally identifiable information are discussed below. 

**Service Providers**  
We work with third parties who provide services, including but not limited to order processing and fulfillment, credit card clearance, e-commerce affiliation, data analysis and other services of an administrative nature. 

Personally identifiable information, including financial information, is shared with such third parties for the purpose of providing such services. 

Further, we may use selected reputable third parties for marketing and analysis purposes. Some of these third parties may be given access to some, or all, of the information that you provide to us and may use cookies or other tracking technologies in connection with providing their services. To the extent that we provide your personally identifiable information to such third parties, we seek to restrict their ability to use such information for their own marketing purposes; however, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies or practices of such third parties. 

**Sale of Our Company**  
As a natural consequence of the development of our company, we could be sold to another company. In the event that we are acquired by another company or a significant portion of our assets is sold to another company, all of the customer information including both financial records and consumer information that we have collected may be transferred to the new company. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
We do not disclose an individual customer's personally identifiable information to third parties for third-party direct marketing purposes if we have received and processed a request from that customer not to have his or her personal information shared for this purpose. You may submit this type of opt-out request by email using our Public Relations web form or to the following mailing address: Customer Service, Linspire, Inc., 9333 Genesee Avenue, 3rd Floor, San Diego, CA 92121. In addition, we also allow you to decide whether you want to receive further marketing information from us. If you do not want Linspire to send to you announcements or special offers by email, please email us using our Public Relations web form with "Remove" in the subject line. Please allow up to two weeks for your request to be processed. You may also edit your email subscription settings in your [My.Linspire](https://shop.linspire.com/user/mylindows_welcome.php). account under the "My Email Subscriptions" page. 

**Online Surveys**  
Linspire sometimes administers online surveys in connection with the Site in which we ask you for demographic information and opinions. We do not ask you for personally identifiable information as part of a survey. We use the collected survey data on an aggregated basis to better understand the needs of all of our customers. 

**Certain Non-Marketing Uses**  
Linspire may send to you periodic announcements regarding status updates, service changes concerning the Site and other administrative matters.

Subject to applicable law, we reserve the right to release information concerning any Site visitor where such visitor is believed to be in violation of his or her obligations to us, is partaking (or is suspected of partaking) in any illegal activity, in response to civil subpoenas and discovery requests, to protect the interests of Linspire, our customers or others, and as otherwise permitted or required by law. 

**Third Party Websites**  
Emails from Linspire or its business partners, and the Site itself, may contain links to other Internet websites, including sites that may or may not be owned or operated by Linspire. Unless otherwise explicitly stated, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites, including such sites' use of any information (such as IP number, browser type or operating system) collected when email recipients or Site visitors click through links to those sites. If you visit such websites, we encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of the sites. 

**How Your Information Is Stored**  
Linspire seeks to use reasonable security measures to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personally identifiable information that is under our control. Unfortunately, no security system, or system of transmitting data over the Internet, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result of the foregoing, while we seek to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee the security of our servers, the means by which information is transmitted between your computer and Linspire's servers, or any information provided to us or to any third party through or in connection with the Site. You provide all such information at your own risk. 

**How To Update Your Personal Information**  
If you have signed up for an account with Linspire, you may update your mailing address, email address, name changes, Forum name, or billing information by accessing your [My.Linspire](https://shop.linspire.com/user/mylindows_welcome.php) account, where you can log into your account to review and update your personal information. 

**Linspire Forums**  
This Site may make chat rooms, forums and/or message boards available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. Please note that your default Forum name is your email address. You may change your Forum name in your [My.Linspire](https://shop.linspire.com/user/mylindows_welcome.php) account. 

**Contacting Linspire**   
If you have any questions about this Policy, the data collection and usage practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, or if you wish to report a violation of this Policy, please contact: 

Customer Service  
Linspire, Inc.  
9333 Genesee Ave. 3rd Floor   
San Diego, CA 92121  
email Support.

**Quality Customer Experience**  
Linspire is committed to quality customer experience. We are constantly reviewing your feedback to improve and enhance your user experience. You can tell us what you think by contacting our customer support department at <http://www.linspire.com/ask>. 

|    
---|---|---
